<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Bluetooth | Ting Wai's Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://ctingwai.github.com/blog/categories/bluetooth/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://ctingwai.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2014-02-15T15:00:38+08:00</updated>
  <id>http://ctingwai.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Chong Ting Wai]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Blueproximity for KDE4 Configuration]]></title>
    <link href="http://ctingwai.github.com/blog/2014/02/15/blueproximity-for-kde4/"/>
    <updated>2014-02-15T14:35:00+08:00</updated>
    <id>http://ctingwai.github.com/blog/2014/02/15/blueproximity-for-kde4</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>BlueProximity is a great addition to Linux, it adds a little of extra security
for you Linux machine. For those who don't know what it is, here's an excerpt
from BlueProximity:</p>

<p><blockquote><p>This software helps you add a little more security to your desktop. It does so<br/>by detecting one of your bluetooth devices, most likely your mobile phone, and<br/>keeping track of its distance. If you move away from your computer and the<br/>distance is above a certain level (no measurement in meters is possible) for a<br/>given time, it automatically locks your desktop (or starts any other shell<br/>command you want).</p></p><p><p>Once away your computer awaits its master back - if you are nearer than a given<br/>level for a set time your computer unlocks magically without any interaction<br/>(or starts any other shell command you want).</p><footer><strong>BlueProximity</strong> <cite><a href='http://blueproximity.sourceforge.net'>blueproximity.sourceforge.net/&hellip;</a></cite></footer></blockquote></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The problem I found when configuring BlueProximity on my Linux machine is the
commands, if you are on Gnome, nearly no configuration is needed, but I am on
KDE 4.x. So, here's the command I used to get it working on my machine:</p>

<ul>
<li>Lock command: <code>qdbus-qt4 org.kde.screensaver /ScreenSaver Lock</code></li>
<li>Unlock command: <code>qdbus-qt4 | grep kscreenlocker_greet | xargs -I {} qdbus-qt4 {} /MainApplication quit</code></li>
<li>Proximity command: <code>qdbus-qt4 org.freedesktop.ScreenSaver /ScreenSaver SimulateUserActivity</code></li>
</ul>


<p>If you are not using <code>qdbus-qt4</code>, substitute it with <code>qdbus</code>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
